<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>kaleidopunk</title>
  <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-12-10T11:53:52+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://kaleidopunk.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>buddhamagnet</name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Boneflash</title>
    <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/10/10/boneflash/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-10T09:47:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/10/10/boneflash</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been consumed of late by a strange force. Increasingly sad about the human race and its reckless and damaging actions, I&amp;#8217;m feeling deep and wide. It&amp;#8217;s not despair, even though it makes my heart heavy.
I guess it&amp;#8217;s a sadness that people can&amp;#8217;t seem to realise how endless and powerful the cosmos is. That we spend so much time either engaged in fruitless and trivial pursuits, controlled by
our tools and distracted by posion static, or hurting one another. I was on the train this morning, utterly calm and trying to hold on to that feeling as I approached the city, and for
a second I saw people lit up, illuiminated in a green flash, could see their bones and blood, pumping and cracking, all cast from the same mould but sundered and alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not a flake. But I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking more and more about British visionaries like Blake, connecting hard with history and the ancient history our culture is built on. Yes it was bloody
and ignorant for the most part, but somewhere along the way, as we&amp;#8217;ve evolved our technology and science, we&amp;#8217;ve lost a fundamental conduit to the primal and eternal. I&amp;#8217;m bringing that back
online in my own life to the best of my ability. In bushcraft, in strong connections with people, in a keen awareness of the wild and tribal. And not in a hippie sense. It&amp;#8217;s the only way
our demented and broken species will survive.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>London dreams</title>
    <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/30/london-dreams/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-30T15:55:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/30/london-dreams</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Why, Sir, you find no man, at all intellectual, who is willing to leave London. No, Sir, when a man is tired of London, he is tired of life; for there is in London all that life can afford.&amp;#8221;
— Samuel Johnson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I am mulling over this quote will become apparent soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Breathe deep</title>
    <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/23/breath-deep/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-23T13:07:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/23/breath-deep</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was reading Pablo Neruda on the train in today. That kind of grasp of language, that totality of vision, terrify and enthrall me. But I
know something. Sometimes (a lot of the time) I find it hard to write words. I&amp;#8217;m lazy. I don&amp;#8217;t trust the magnetic currents that drive me.
I need to surrender more and worry less. Even when I don&amp;#8217;t get there, I have a keen awareness that I&amp;#8217;m part of an endless, blazing continuum
of writers and poets. Luminous souls. People who fought, and fight, the debasement of the word and the degradation of the spirit. Sometimes
I can almost touch them, and sometimes when that current is flowing freely, the most incredible synchronicity engages and makes the maddest
things manifest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to learn to dive deeper, conserve my oxygen, dive into the depths where strange forms shiver. I need to learn how to hold my breath.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Unbound TV</title>
    <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/19/unbound-tv/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-19T15:26:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/19/unbound-tv</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Unbound were on Channel 4 news a few days ago!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object id=&quot;flashObj&quot; width=&quot;370&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; classid=&quot;clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000&quot; codebase=&quot;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=9,0,47,0&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;bgcolor&quot; value=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;flashVars&quot; value=&quot;videoId=1160713641001&amp;playerID=69900095001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAEabvr4~,Wtd2HT-p_VhJQ6tgdykx3j23oh1YN-2U&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;base&quot; value=&quot;http://admin.brightcove.com&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;seamlesstabbing&quot; value=&quot;false&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;swLiveConnect&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowScriptAccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; flashVars=&quot;videoId=1160713641001&amp;playerID=69900095001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAEabvr4~,Wtd2HT-p_VhJQ6tgdykx3j23oh1YN-2U&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true&quot; base=&quot;http://admin.brightcove.com&quot; name=&quot;flashObj&quot; width=&quot;370&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; seamlesstabbing=&quot;false&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; swLiveConnect=&quot;true&quot; allowScriptAccess=&quot;always&quot; pluginspage=&quot;http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Noon magics</title>
    <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/18/noonmagics/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-18T17:30:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/18/noonmagics</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love synchronicity. I&amp;#8217;ve been planning a website devoted to word experiments for some time.
Walking in the park today, I suddenly thought of Jeff Noon, the author of Vurt and other weird
and wonderful fictions and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metamorphiction.com/index.php/printed/cobralingus/&quot;&gt;Cobralingus&lt;/a&gt; experiment. I decided to get in touch with Jeff to
see whether he wanted to get involved and did a quick search for his name on Twitter. The third
tweet I saw was by &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/furiousgecko&quot;&gt;Colin Wilson&lt;/a&gt; saying that &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jeffnoon&quot;&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt; had suddenly appeared on Twitter. Today. My
heart skipped a beat. The internal structure of the universe is strange and powerful, and
sometimes the surface is so thin we can travel space, time and mind in an instant. It&amp;#8217;s
palpable.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Unbound live</title>
    <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/17/unbound-live/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-17T17:28:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/17/unbound-live</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The event I mentioned in a previous post was great. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/paul_clarke/sets/72157627656885754/&quot;&gt;Pictures speak louder than words&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Cave projections</title>
    <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/10/cave-projections/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-10T18:31:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/10/cave-projections</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I returned from a family trip to Spain last week and as I bleared my way through Gatwick
at 2 a.m. I bumped into Ian Hislop. It&amp;#8217;s always a little hallucinogenic seeing a well-known
face in the flesh, even more so at that kind of hour. It messes with your face recognition
wetware. Ian was standing, looking a little nervous, listening to his driver drone on about
the varying degrees of fascism exhibited by police forces across the land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The encounter had another effect on me. I am growing increasingly media-sick, tired of
sensationalism, bad reporting, rampant corruption and crass commercialism and the relegation
of many forms of journalism and analysis to branches of the entertainment industry. And it
struck me that there is a cure. Not to turn everything off and disconnect. But just be aware
that media, if not arbiters of truth, are illusory, static. Watching this nervous and tired
man in the skin, contrasting it with the images and sounds of biting satire and wit I have
observed through TV, I realise that I put far too much store in modern media and the cave
projections it throws up in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s dew on grass, bubbles and mind pop. All I really need to do is listen deep to the workings
of my heart. The only booming voice I should heed is that of the word demon that drives me. If
I care for people, connect hard and produce human product with use and value every day, all is well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Books are now in your hands</title>
    <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/07/books-are-now-in-your-hands/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-07T15:33:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/07/books-are-now-in-your-hands</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have had the good fortune to provide coding hands on and off for the last few weeks for &lt;a href=&quot;http://unbound.co.uk&quot;&gt;unbound&lt;/a&gt;,
a wonderful idea, kind of like kickstarter for books but with so much more going on from the initial book pitch right
up to printing, binding and delivery. Great people with a great vision. On Monday September 12th I&amp;#8217;ll be popping along to
their 5 X 15 event at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tabernaclew11.com&quot;&gt;The Tabernacle&lt;/a&gt;, which should be a wordy hoot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;345&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/de9CQA7G6vk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What makes a perfect weekend</title>
    <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/07/perfect-weekend/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-07T14:21:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/07/perfect-weekend</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A wonderfully minimal video from my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/documentally&quot;&gt;documentally&lt;/a&gt; with audio magic from &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mcfontaine&quot;&gt;mcfontaine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/28599563?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Attack The cortex</title>
    <link href="http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/07/attack-the-cortex/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-07T11:02:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://kaleidopunk.com/blog/2011/09/07/attack-the-cortex</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So looks like I finally found a blogging engine and format I like. I&amp;#8217;ve used all the popular
hosted solutions over the years, from Wordpress to Tumblr and Posterous, and even though I&amp;#8217;ve
seen the benefits and convenience of all three, at heart I&amp;#8217;m a hacker and wanted a lightweight
solution totally under my control. I toyed with a combination of open source technologies before
settling on this - the &lt;a href=&quot;http://octopress.org&quot;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; framework for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; blogging engine. Written in &lt;a href=&quot;http://ruby-lang.org&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt;,
a Japanese programming language optimised for happiness and, as I&amp;#8217;ve mentioned before, a language that attracts me for all the wrong reasons, technically speaking. I love the aesthetic, the vibe, and the impossibly hip culture. A computer programming language that attacks the literary cortex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog is given wings by &lt;a href=&quot;http://gitscm.org&quot;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;, a distributed version control system. For me
this is a critical part of the machine. It means I can clone the blog, reproduce it anywhere
and reanimate it if the current hosting platform (the spellbinding &lt;a href=&quot;http://heroku.com&quot;&gt;heroku&lt;/a&gt;) goes away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also means that contributions for now are handled in a rather geeky way. If you want to
contribute, fork the blog on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/buddhamagnet/kaleidopunk&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; and issue a
pull request. Trust me, git is worth knowing for reasons far beyond geek. It gives your content legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is my blog in it&amp;#8217;s fourth or fifth mutation. A kaleidopunk manifesto. A place for me
to explore books, words, hacker culture, stories and sounds. I promise I&amp;#8217;ll stop banging on about
the technology for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
